If you are an auto driver or you have any
kind of auto which
you want to insure through your mobile, then
in today's video I am going to
tell you how you
can check yourself through your mobile
how much your auto insurance will cost.
Apart from this, if you find it right then
how will you be able to complete the insurance,
I will tell you all those things in this video, so
let's get started, so hi everyone,
my name is Vijay and you are watching
Vijay Solution, so for auto insurance, it is
necessary that you have
your vehicle number, that is, whatever the
vehicle number of the auto is, you will
need it there, along with this, for KYC, you will
need the PAN card of the person in whose name the auto is. If you have all these details, then
I will tell you how you will do the insurance,
what you have to do for that, first of all
you will need the link of the
website from which you want to do the insurance, although
you can do it through Google2,
I will tell you where to find the link, so
assume that you are watching this video,
what you have to do is just below this video, here  But there is a
comment section, you have to
simply click on it, as soon as you
click on it, a link will
appear, what you have to do is click on it, as soon as
you click on it, this
website will open, now you have to
write your auto number here, whatever will be your
auto number, I have given the auto
number here, the vehicle number which is written on the number plate,
and
after that I click on search,
when I click on search, it will
automatically come in this way in
which the vehicle number and other details will
come automatically, if you do not know then you will have to enter them
one by one, you will get the
option, in this way,
you will have to select whichever is there, let's say
it has come in my case, so that's why I am directly
coming down here and
clicking on next, when I click on next, it will
come like this, now you are being
asked what kind of policy you want to do, so here you
get two options, one is comprehensive and the
other is third party.
What is the difference between these two, let me tell you.
Many people also call comprehensive as first party. In this, your
vehicle is also covered and
if someone gets harmed by your vehicle, then he is also covered.
So this is an all-in-one thing.
If you want everything in one insurance,
then you should take comprehensive, you will get
everything in it. The second one is
third party, which is a little
less expensive than comprehensive
and in this, the police
cannot fine you because this
insurance is valid, so the
police will not fine you. The
second advantage of this is that suppose
tomorrow someone gets harmed by your vehicle, then the
insurance company will compensate for it,
you do not have to do that.
So it depends on you
which type of insurance you want to take.
Now, whatever type of insurance you want,
you have to choose that here. So,
if you want third party, then you have to choose
towards third party and if you
want first party, then the blue one here has to be moved to this side, in
this way it will come.
It depends on you
how to do it, let me do the third part, on
this side after that it is said previous
year policy, so here in previous year
policy you have to tell whether the previous
policy is comprehensive, meaning it
is first party or third party or the expiry
date and which company it belongs to, you will also have to tell that
if you know all these things
and you have insurance, meaning your previous
insurance has not failed yet, then you
can give the details here, if you do not know then
what you have to do is simple, here
it is on the yes side, if you change it to no, then there will be
no need to give it and
after that you are seeing pay view course here,
you have to click on it,
after which all the plans will
come here, only two plans are shown here,
but if there is any other
insurance company available in your area which is
offering policy bazaar, then all its details will
come here, a lot of details of other different companies will also come,
so you can see what has come now,
P is written here, meaning it belongs to the digit company, it is
third party and its  It will cost Rs. 883, it is
being told here, so this
is third party, if you want to do first party then
its ID is 0600 and its ID is also 0000,
that means the value of the vehicle is
0000. Now suppose you are doing first party, if
you find it less then you can increase it,
for that you have to click on it,
from here you will
select the maximum one, click on update,
whatever it is will get updated, of course
here is the digit P, it is only one company, so it is
not putting more than 00 for it because it is an
old vehicle, so for now, suppose you have it, then
here you will get to know which
insurance of which company, you will get to know
how much it will cost here,
now in this insurance you will come to know
how much it will cost. Now, when we do
insurance, you want that
in it, for example, the
owner of the vehicle, if suppose the
auto is in your name, then you
can take your insurance, it costs
approximately Rs. 50, whatever yours is in that  Insurance of 15 lakhs
is available, similarly if a
driver is driving someone else and you
want his insurance, then that too can be done for a very low price,
but it is not for 15 lakhs,
it is for one to two lakhs, okay, and in the
same way, you can do it for the passenger as well, if
people want zero dip session, then
you can add everything in it if you want,
I will tell you how to add it, what you have to do
for that, you have to click on this, you are
looking for the add-on option,
click on it, after that you will get the option
here, you can see here the option of zero dip, you will
select it, after that you will
get the option of personal accident cover, you
can see that all the options are given in it, owner driver and driver,
you can choose whatever you want,
if you do not want it then you can skip it
and after that click on submit, when you
click on submit, it will
check it again and tell you, so you have to
wait a little, now you
can see here that it has come here,
but the zero dip has not come, that is,
only the paid driver's option is given  If the owner
driver that I have added has come, then if it
comes then there will be a tick mark here, otherwise it will
either not be there or even if it is there then there will be a
cross mark, so understand that you are
not getting any item, okay now let me
assume that you do not want this because it is an
optional thing, then you can remove it from here,
like if I remove it from here
and click on submit again, then it will
come as normal, it depends on you whether you
want to take the additional or not, it is
not going to make any difference,
or if you take it then the add-on gets covered, that
means you get the facility of other things as well, for now let me
tell you
that suppose you find the insurance price good, then
I will tell you how to do it, so for that
suppose
you have to do this, then you are seeing this simple thing,
you will click on the price written on it,
after that something like this will
come down here, here the
owner of the vehicle, whatever his name is, you have to
check it on the RC, whose name is there, you have to
give the name of that person here, you can give the mobile number of
any person  You can give it, there is no
problem, you have to give your email ID here,
whatever your ABC email ID is, you will give it
here, after that, whatever is being
said here as address, whatever your address is,
you have to give it here or it is
also written in the RC, so you can check it from there also and give it, so the
rest of the details
like state, city, all these things have come automatically,
if it is not there then you have to give it,
if it is there then there is no problem, now
come down and simply click on it and the
next step is visible, you have to click on it,
now it has come here in this way,
now you can see here that the
engine number is being asked here, sometimes the engine
number is taken automatically, if it is not there then
you have to check it from the RC and whatever it is,
you can see it here, after
verification it comes immediately in this way, sometimes
it takes time, so you will have to
wait a little and after doing this you will click on summary and
payment, after which
again the details will come here, you do
not have to do anything here, just look at it
You have to click on Secure,
after which it will rotate in this manner,
so you have to wait a little and
this way it will take you to the payment page. Here
you will get the option of Debit Card,
Credit Card, Net Banking, UPI, Wallet
and EMI, whichever way you want to make the payment. If you have an
ATM card, then select it. If you have a credit
card, then you can do it through net banking or through
e-pay in this way. If
you can
see it, click on it. Here
you will see the UPI ID. If you are facing
difficulty in copying it, then
click on it. Here you will
get the option to copy it. You will simply
click on it. You will come back to your
page and you have to paste it here.
I have pasted it here.
Now this UPI ID has come but if you
see this UPI ID, then it is given after the rate,
which is not to be
given here because the option after @ is
given here. So if I remove this from here, then
it has been removed and and
what was after the rate, okay,
you do not have to press the back button after making the payment.
You have to
come back to this page in your mobile in this way and
wait here, when you wait
here, the payment will be automatically confirmed, it may take
one second, two, four, five seconds
or 10 seconds and as soon as it is confirmed,
you will immediately get the option to download the policy copy,
there
as soon as you
click on the option to download the policy copy, your policy copy will be
downloaded and you
can print it and keep it as the original, this will serve as your
original, in this way
I have told that if you have any
pickup van, then how can you insure it, if you have
any problem,
you can call on the number given below by me, I
will help you completely, for now, this is all that is given
in this video, thank you very much,
which is not to be given here
because the option after @ rate is
given here, so if I remove this one from here, then it has been
removed and the OK which was after rate has
come, you will click on it, after which it will appear in
this way, you will have the option to make the
payment here  If you get the option, you can see
that it is the same amount. You just have to
click on Pay and make the
payment in the same way as you do UPI to someone, that is, at a shop or anywhere. You have to make the payment in the same way. As soon as you make the payment,
when the payment is done, you do
not have to press the back button. After making the payment,
you have to come back to this page in your mobile in this
way and
wait here. When you wait here, the
payment will be automatically confirmed. It may take one second,
two, four, five seconds or 10 seconds.
As soon as it is confirmed, you will immediately
get the option to download the policy.
As soon as you
click on the option to download your policy copy, your policy copy will be downloaded
and you can print it and
keep it as the original. This will serve as your original. In
this way, we have
told you how you
can do auto insurance yourself. If you face
any kind of problem,
you can call on my number given below.
I will definitely help you. For now,
Thank you so much for the video